Hello, my friends, and welcome again to the complete data structure and algorithms course in this
exercise, we are asked to write the function to append the new node at the end of the list, so appending
means that we are adding new nodes into the end of the list.
Consider a new list.
Here we have our add list linked list.
We have this second none and this will.
Reference the third note, and this is for the not.
We are asking in this question to write a function that adds at the end of the list, and you knew not
such that this is the new not called number six.
OK, so it was a reference after eight to six and six by reference to no.
This is the new note that we are going to happen post the video and think about this function that we
are going to make.
By the way, we have mentioned this in the lecture, so please go back to the lectures and see how we
can make an attempt in, you know, at the end of that list.
So in order to do that, we are going to create a new function.
Public void called append not.
OK.
This append nod to the end of the list.
So it will took the data only.
So new data that data that we hear of that is new, not that we are going to append.
So the first step we are going to create new.
Not new.
No, not new.
Not that we have seen before, you know?
OK, and it contains the new data we are creating.
Then, you know, the second way or the second step.
If the linked list is empty, then make this new not as happy if the new or the list is empty.
Make this.
New not as happy.
OK, so if we had equal equals to null, then had equal to a new nugget and that contains new, not
a new date.
OK, and then return.
We are making this as a the head of the link, at least the empty link list.
Now the third step.
Third step, is this in your new novel, is it going to be the last, you know, as last?
Not new, not the next equal to no.
OK.
This is very simple.
This is the basics of Lincoln blessed that the last known word reference to the nut.
OK, now at the fourth step, we are going to traverse until the last.
Not OK.
Traverse.
Then the last nod nod last equals prepared.
And while last thought next does not equal to none
last year unless the next day, this is very simple.
And five.
Change the next of last night.
So last the next equal to new none.
It's very simple.
And then return, I'm making them with them with Java, because the lecture, we have lectured them
in sea language and also in Java and the practice we love to make the practice, which are with Java,
because many interviews and many universities, their majority are asking their questions.
And Java?
OK.
So.
Let's test this method.
This standard, by the way, I have to tell you that I have written all the complexity of all the methods.
So print list it will go to, there are two to the last by passing all the nodes.
So if this complexity is of the complexity of push at beginning would be of one because it's making
it constant work.
It's just pushing and not at the constant at the beginning and insert after also all of one because
it's making a constant amount of work by and by knowing the previous not going to the previous note
and inserting one element after append node.
This would be that complexity of all of.
And because it goes through all the elements to insert the number more than you not.
OK.
So these are the complexity for every method that I have read in the previous exercises.
It's very simple.
Now let's test our method.
It's exercise number 44 spending new, not new nodes at end.
So link atlas start up and then not.
We are going to insert number six at the last element of the last note at of that atlas.
Let's see for did the three and this is six.
So we have inserted they're not the new note that contains No.
Six at the end of their linked list.
So guys, it's very important to practice these exercises and understand them because they are very,
very important and these are the basics and they're intermediate.
Next, we are going to move to that more and more.